{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Lake Superior ","incorrectAnswers":["Lake Baikal","Lake Huron","Lake Titicaca"],"question":"Which Is The Largest Freshwater Lake by surface area?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Quebec","incorrectAnswers":["Queen","Qualify","Qwerty"],"question":"What word is used in the NATO Phonetic Alphabet for the letter Q?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Uganda","incorrectAnswers":["Portugal","Uruguay","Uzbekistan"],"question":"Which region of the world uses '.ug' at the end of its web addresses?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"William Shakespeare","incorrectAnswers":["Arthur C. Clarke","Isaac Newton","Enid Blyton"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Mother Gooſe’s Melody'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Just like the ones I used to know","incorrectAnswers":["Sharing kisses in the snow","We'll be going with the flow","Walking to your favourite show"],"question":"Bing Crosby famously sang 'I'm dreaming of a white Christmas'', what is the next line?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Alec Baldwin","incorrectAnswers":["Donald Sutherland","Gary Oldman","Sean Connery"],"question":"Which actor has featured in roles including 30 Rock and The Departed?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Robert Bell","incorrectAnswers":["Mark DuPont","Lawrence Jones","Gary Helman"],"question":"What was the real name of Kool, of Kool and the Gang fame?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Edgar Allan Poe","incorrectAnswers":["Stephen King","Nathaniel Hawthorne","Mario Puzo"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Fall of the House of Usher'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Charles Dickens","incorrectAnswers":["Mark Twain","William Shakespeare","Jane Austen"],"question":"Who wrote 'Oliver Twist'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Pieter Bruegel the Elder","incorrectAnswers":["Georges Seurat","Pablo Picasso","Hokusai"],"question":"Which artist painted \"Landscape with the Fall of Icarus\"","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"ABBA","incorrectAnswers":["In Flames","HammerFall","Katatonia"],"question":"Which band includes 'Agnetha Fältskog'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Sleepless in Seattle","incorrectAnswers":["A Kiss from a Vampire","Forrest Gump","Toy Story"],"question":"What was the name of the popular '90s film starring Tom Hanks and Meg Ryan?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Robert Duvall","incorrectAnswers":["Samuel L. Jackson","Daniel Day-Lewis","Orson Welles"],"question":"Which actor played the role of Lt. Col. Bill Kilgore in Apocalypse Now?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Carcassonne","incorrectAnswers":["Risk","Monopoly","Checkers"],"question":"In which classic board game do players collect cards and build a city?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Latin","incorrectAnswers":["German","Sanskrit","Greek"],"question":"What was the official language of the Holy Roman Empire?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Shere Khan","incorrectAnswers":["Baloo","Bagheera","King Louie"],"question":"In the 1967 animated film 'The Jungle Book', what is the name of the tiger character?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Anne Frank","incorrectAnswers":["Friedrich Engels","Michael Ende","Karl May"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Diary of Anne Frank'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Simon & Garfunkel","incorrectAnswers":["Soinny & Cher","Sam & Dave","The Carpenters"],"question":"Which American music duo wrote the song 'El cóndor pasa'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Kylie Minogue","incorrectAnswers":["Madonna","Mika","Hikaru Utada"],"question":"Which Australian singer released the song 'Can't Get You Out of My Head'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"The crew of a spacecraft encounter a deadly lifeform after investigating a transmission.","incorrectAnswers":["The life of the lawyer who became the famed leader of the Indian revolts against the British rule.","An insurance representative lets a housewife seduce him into a scheme of insurance fraud and murder.","After the death of a tycoon, reporters scramble to uncover the meaning of his final utterance."],"question":"What is the plot of the movie Alien?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Paul McCartney","incorrectAnswers":["Barbra Streisand","Elton John","Bruce Springsteen"],"question":"Who Wrote The Theme Song For The James Bond Movie \"Live & Let Die\"","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"fermentation","incorrectAnswers":["the Islam","interactions among organisms and the water cycle","music in society, usually non-western music"],"question":"What is Zymology the study of?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Asunción","incorrectAnswers":["Praia","Vilnius","Castries"],"question":"What is the capital city of Paraguay?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Myanmar","incorrectAnswers":["Egypt","Italy","Tanzania"],"question":"In which country would you find the Ancient City of Bagan?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Stephen King","incorrectAnswers":["George Orwell","John Steinbeck","Tom Clancy"],"question":"Who wrote the book 'The Shining' on which the 1980 Stanley Kubrick film was based?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Washington Capitals","incorrectAnswers":["Washington Eathquakes","Washington Celtics","Washington Jets"],"question":"Which of these is a hockey team based in Washington?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Parka","incorrectAnswers":["Peacoat","Trenchcoat","Puffer Jacket"],"question":"What type of coat originates from the Inuit people of the Arctic?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Maggie Smith","incorrectAnswers":["Kathy Bates","Sandra Bæ Hovedr","Kirsten Dunst"],"question":"Which actress has starred in both Downton Abbey and the Harry Potter series of films?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Mexico","incorrectAnswers":["Bhutan","Japan","Brazil"],"question":"Where in the world would you most expect to be served a taco?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Mahjong","incorrectAnswers":["Sudoku","Shogi","Go"],"question":"What game involves tiles with dots, cracks, and bams?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Defense and thermoregulation","incorrectAnswers":["Digging","Attracting prey","Climbing"],"question":"What was the purpose of the spikes on the back of the Stegosaurus?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Phosphoric acid","incorrectAnswers":["Potassium Nitrate","Ammonia","Asbestos"],"question":"Which substance has the chemical formula  H3PO4?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Eris","incorrectAnswers":["Razr","Mercury","Zeus"],"question":"Who is the Greek equivalent of the Roman god Discordia?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"1965","incorrectAnswers":["1953","1959","1971"],"question":"The Sound of Music was released in which year?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"A Portrait of the Artist as a Young Man","incorrectAnswers":["Little Women","David Copperfield","Jane Eyre"],"question":"In which book does the character 'Stephen Dedalus' appear?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Tubular pasta","incorrectAnswers":["Strand pasta","Stuffed pasta","Shaped pasta"],"question":"What type of pasta is cannelloni?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Ireland ","incorrectAnswers":["Canada","New Zealand","Australia"],"question":"Where Is The Glenveagh National Park?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"U2","incorrectAnswers":["Public Image Ltd.","The Script","The Cure"],"question":"Which Irish rock band released the song 'I Still Haven't Found What I'm Looking For'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Foo Fighters","incorrectAnswers":["Anti-Flag","The Pussycat Dolls","Three 6 Mafia"],"question":"Which band includes 'Dave Grohl'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Sow","incorrectAnswers":["A Gander","A Jenny","A Hen"],"question":"What is a female pig known as?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Rain Man","incorrectAnswers":["The Godfather","The 400 Blows","Fast Times at Ridgemont High"],"question":"Which film contains the character 'Raymond Babbitt'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Zimbabwe","incorrectAnswers":["Pakistan","Kenya","Panama"],"question":"Southern Rhodesia became what country in 1980?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Santiago","incorrectAnswers":["Buenos Aires","San Salvador","Lima"],"question":"Which of these cities is in Chile?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Madonna","incorrectAnswers":["Eric Clapton","Nicki Minaj","Alanis Morissette"],"question":"Which American musician sung 'Like a Prayer'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Napoleon","incorrectAnswers":["Hitler","Genghis Khan","Charlemagne"],"question":"Whose army did Admiral Nelson defeat at the battle of Trafalgar?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Copernicus","incorrectAnswers":["Kepler","Galileo","Hubble"],"question":"Which Polish astronomer has craters on the moon and Mars named after him?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"The Catcher in the Rye","incorrectAnswers":["Wise Blood","To the Lighthouse","Winnie the Pooh"],"question":"Which book contains the character 'Holden Caulfield'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"People's Republic of China","incorrectAnswers":["Bhutan","North Korea","Myanmar"],"question":"Which of these countries borders Mongolia?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"present-day landforms, traditionally on Earth but with increasing frequency on nearby planetary objects","incorrectAnswers":["weather","sex","life in outer space"],"question":"What is Geomorphology the study of?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Vietnam","incorrectAnswers":["Slovenia","Guatemala","Nepal"],"question":"Hanoi is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Scapula","incorrectAnswers":["Sternum","Humerus","Clavicle"],"question":"What is the medical name for the shoulder blade?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Mozart","incorrectAnswers":["Beethoven","Stravinsky","Tchaikovsky"],"question":"Who wrote the Opera 'The Magic Flute'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Swan Lake","incorrectAnswers":["The Nutcracker","Romeo and Juliet","Sleeping Beauty"],"question":"In which classic ballet do Prince Siegfried and Odette drown themselves at the end?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Quiche","incorrectAnswers":["Omelette","Frittata","Pizza"],"question":"What type of food has a version called \"Lorraine\"?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A murmuration","incorrectAnswers":["A barren","A pack","A shrewdness"],"question":"What is the word for a group of starlings?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Sausage ","incorrectAnswers":["Cheese","Bread","Cake"],"question":"Popular in the Netherlands, what type of food is a frikandel?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Kid","incorrectAnswers":["A Foal","A Poult","A Spiderling"],"question":"A young goat is known as what?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Scalene triangle","incorrectAnswers":["Equilateral triangle","Isosceles triangle","Parallelogram"],"question":"What is the name of a triangle with three sides of unequal length?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Edward Jenner","incorrectAnswers":["Francis Crick","Edith Bower","Marcel Decroix"],"question":"Who developed the vaccine for smallpox?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Fauna","incorrectAnswers":["Mammalia","Carnivora","Aquatica"],"question":"When referring to an ecosystem, what word is often paired with \"Flora\" to refer to the animals?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Pterodactyl","incorrectAnswers":["Triceratops","Stegosaurus","Brachiosaurus"],"question":"Which of the following is not a dinosaur?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Indo-European","incorrectAnswers":["Sino-Tibetan","Dravidian","Koreanic"],"question":"The language 'Portuguese' belongs to which language family?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"United States","incorrectAnswers":["South Africa","France","Spain"],"question":"Which country hosted the 1994 FIFA World Cup?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"ABBA","incorrectAnswers":["In Flames","HammerFall","Katatonia"],"question":"Which Swedish pop group released the song 'Waterloo'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"4","incorrectAnswers":["1","2","3"],"question":"How many times was Franklin Roosevelt elected president of the USA?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Vegetables","incorrectAnswers":["Bread","Soup","Wine"],"question":"Generally speaking, on a restaurant menu, what might be presented in the style referred to as Macedoine?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Rakia","incorrectAnswers":["Sombai","Schnapps","Jenever"],"question":"Which of these drinks would you associate with Croatia?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Khonsu","incorrectAnswers":["Re","Horus","Anubis"],"question":"Who was the Ancient Egyptian moon god?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Graceland","incorrectAnswers":["Neverland","Jackson Ranch","Amity"],"question":"What Was The Name Of Elvis Presley's Home?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Bertolt Brecht","incorrectAnswers":["Giuseppe Verdi","Robert Wilson","Maurice Maeterlinck"],"question":"Who wrote the \"Threepenny\" opera?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Buck","incorrectAnswers":["A Jack","A Macho","A Billy"],"question":"What is the word for a male mouse?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"La Paz","incorrectAnswers":["Lhasa","Quito","Kathmandu"],"question":"What is the world's highest city?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"King Kong","incorrectAnswers":["Frankenstein","Dracula","The Wolfman"],"question":"What is the name of the 1933 film in which a character delivers the famous line 'Oh, no.  It wasn't the airplanes.  It was Beauty killed the Beast'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"India","incorrectAnswers":["China","United States","France"],"question":"Which country produces more theatrical feature films every year than any other country?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Rihanna","incorrectAnswers":["Drake","Nicki Minaj","Ricky Martin"],"question":"Which singer released the song 'Run This Town'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Mars","incorrectAnswers":["Nipples","Abnormalities of the teeth","Word origins"],"question":"What is areology the study of?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Grenada","incorrectAnswers":["Barbados","Ireland","Mauritania"],"question":"Saint George's is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Peace be with you","incorrectAnswers":["God is good","Where's the swimming pool","Thank you"],"question":"What is the meaning of the Arabic \"assalamu alaikum\"?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Drake","incorrectAnswers":["Neil Young","Alanis Morissette","Justin Bieber"],"question":"Which Canadian musician released the album 'Views'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"John Lennon ","incorrectAnswers":["Malcolm X","John F Kennedy","Martin Luther King"],"question":"Who was assassinated on Dec. 8, 1980 in New York City? ","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Beatles","incorrectAnswers":["Deep Purple","Feeder","Uriah Heep"],"question":"Which English rock band released the album 'Help!'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Scream","incorrectAnswers":["Chucky","A Nightmare on Elm Street","Insidious"],"question":"Which series of horror movies were greatly influenced by a painting by Edvard Munch?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Blondie","incorrectAnswers":["The Pussycat Dolls","Three 6 Mafia","The Velvet Underground"],"question":"Which American rock band released the song 'Heart of Glass'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Percussion","incorrectAnswers":["Woodwind","Brass","Stringed"],"question":"What type of instrument is a cymbal?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The White Stripes","incorrectAnswers":["White Rabbit","Whitesnake","White Zombie"],"question":"Which band is fronted by Jack White?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Munich","incorrectAnswers":["Belgrade","Budapest","Rome"],"question":"In 1958 a plane carrying Manchester United home from a match in Belgrade crash during take-off at which city's Airport?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"The Strait Of Gibralter ","incorrectAnswers":["The Bering Strait","The Strait Of Casablanca","The North African Strait"],"question":"What Separates Spain From Morocco?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Narcissism","incorrectAnswers":["Greed","Ego","Obsession"],"question":"In the field of psychiatry, which term means self-love?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Deer ","incorrectAnswers":["Sheep","Pig","Goat"],"question":"From what animal do we get venison?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Venezuela","incorrectAnswers":["Ukraine","Jamaica","Latvia"],"question":"Which of these countries has red on its flag?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Hooking","incorrectAnswers":["Swiping","Checking","Slashing"],"question":"In hockey, what is the penalty called that involves impeding the progress of an opponent with the stick?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Thailand","incorrectAnswers":["Libya","Guatemala","Iraq"],"question":"In which country would you find Ayutthaya Historical Park?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Pan's Labyrinth","incorrectAnswers":["Monsters, Inc.","V for Vendetta","Fight Club"],"question":"Name the movie that matches the following plot summary: 'The stepdaughter of a sadistic army officer escapes into an eerie fantasy world.'","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Akevitt","incorrectAnswers":["Slivovitz","Mama Juana","Gin"],"question":"Which of these drinks would you associate with Norway?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Washington Wizards","incorrectAnswers":["Washington Knicks","Washington Raiders","Washington Red Sox"],"question":"Which of these is a basketball team based in Washington?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Socrates","incorrectAnswers":["Thomas Hobbes","Bertrand Russell","Immanuel Kant"],"question":"Which philosopher famously said 'The only thing I know is that I know nothing'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Beatles","incorrectAnswers":["Deep Purple","Feeder","Uriah Heep"],"question":"Which English rock band released the song 'Sgt. Pepper's Lonely Hearts Club Band'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Jesse Owens","incorrectAnswers":["Carl Lewis","Bruce Jenner","Bob Beamon"],"question":"Who Was The First Athlete To Exceed a Distance Of Eight Metres In The Long Jump In 1935?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"North","incorrectAnswers":["East","West","South"],"question":"If you're in the northern hemisphere, Polaris, the North Star, can be found by looking which direction?","difficulty":"easy"},